<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
  CV for a backend-focused role with an emphasis on event streaming architectures
-->
<resume-content
  xmlns="https://github.com/b-vennes/presume"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="https://github.com/b-vennes/presume cv-schema.xsd"
>

  <header
    name="Branden Vennes"
    email="b.n.vennes@gmail.com"
    github="b-vennes"
    site="www.brandenvennes.com"
    phone="503-277-0678"
  >
    <summary>
      API and backend solutions engineer with 6 years of experience.  Develops high-quality and robust software solutions using a variety of tools including object-oriented and functional languages, SQL and NoSQL databases, and event-driven paradigms.  A strong knowledge of cloud best-practices and a history of deploying dozens of applications to live environments.  AWS cloud practitioner certified.  Expertise in Scala, Java, Go, Python, and TypeScript.
    </summary>
  </header>

  <experience
    business="The Walt Disney Company"
    title="Software Engineer II"
  >
    <start-date year="2022" month="6" />
    <end-date year="2025" month="8" />

    <detail>
      Developed internal services with Scala, PostgreSQL, and AWS supporting development teams in building event-driven applications including replication, aggregation, and lineage tracing for thousands of AWS Kinesis streams processing billions of events each day
    </detail>
    <detail>
      Automated the deployment of Spark data-processing jobs and pipelines, integrating GitHub queries, Jenkins build execution, Databricks API interactions, and Slack notifications to automatically start and manage deployments
    </detail>
    <detail>
      Designed build pipelines using Jenkins and GitHub Actions to generate and publish libraries for interacting with event streams using data schemas ensuring consistency and compatibility for production services
    </detail>
  </experience>

  <experience
    business="Topl"
    title="Blockchain Platform Engineer"
  >
    <start-date year="2021" month="3" />
    <end-date year="2022" month="5" />
    <detail>
      Implemented a ledger query service using an authenticated streaming Protobuf endpoint implemented in Scala with MongoDB for indexing transactions
    </detail>
    <detail>
      Designed and implemented an API for managing staking and wallet keys in blockchain nodes and viewing chain and node metadata
    </detail>
    <detail>
      Maintained critical blockchain node domain rules to ensure application stability, security, and safety while adding features and product updates
    </detail>
    <detail>
      Wrote end-to-end API tests in Postman with CI/CD integration using the Newman test runner providing coverage over API use-cases and example documentation for end users
    </detail>
  </experience>

  <experience
    business="Viewpoint Construction Software"
    title="Software Engineer I &amp; II"
  >
    <start-date year="2019" month="9" />
    <end-date year="2021" month="4" />
    <detail>
      Implemented Angular pages and components, API endpoints and state in C#, and data schemas for the cloud web application providing project planning, organization, and collaboration to key stakeholders of construction projects
    </detail>
    <detail>
      Designed and developed a change order management system using an event-sourcing architecture and synchronization with the comapny's ERP system using Kafka
    </detail>
    <detail>
      Managed an MSSQL database containing hundreds of tables and millions of records with optimized schema design, materialized views, and careful indexing to ensure responsiveness and data consistency
    </detail>
  </experience>

  <experience
    business="Viewpoint Construction Software"
    title="QA Automation Engineer"
  >
    <start-date year="2018" month="8" />
    <end-date year="2019" month="8" />
    <detail>
      Expanded the API and UI automation framework to support QA engineers with writing more robust automated tests
    </detail>
    <detail>
      Maintained automated tests to ensure reliable results from nightly test runs providing useful feedback and support for developers
    </detail>
    <detail>
      Executed API endpoint performance and load tests to verify application platform stability under high-stress
    </detail>
  </experience>

  <education
    school="University of Portland"
    degree="Bachelors of Science"
  >
    <start-date year="2015" month="8" />
    <end-date year="2019" month="5" />
    <detail>Computer Science Major</detail>
    <detail>Mathematics Minor</detail>
  </education>

  <certification name="AWS Cloud Practitioner" />

  <skills group="Application Layer">
    <skill>Languages: Scala, Java, Go, Python, and TypeScript</skill>
    <skill>API Design: REST, Protobuf, and CQRS</skill>
    <skill>Asynchronous and Multithreaded Design</skill>
    <skill>Object-Oriented and Functional Programming</skill>
  </skills>
  <skills group="Data Layer">
    <skill>SQL Databases: PostgreSQL and MSSQL</skill>
    <skill>Document Databases: AWS DynamoDB and MongoDB</skill>
    <skill>Graph Databases: Neo4j and AWS Neptune</skill>
    <skill>Data Streams and Analytics: Databricks, Spark, AWS Kinesis, and Apache Kafka</skill>
  </skills>
  <skills group="DevOps">
    <skill>Containers: Docker, Docker Swarm, and Kubernetes</skill>
    <skill>Terraform</skill>
    <skill>Build Pipelines: GitHub Actions, Jenkins, and Circle CI</skill>
    <skill>AWS IAM, Cloudwatch, and Cloudformation</skill>
  </skills>

</resume-content>
