<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
  Empty CV with name and companies filled out.
-->
<resume-content
  xmlns="https://github.com/b-vennes/presume"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="https://github.com/b-vennes/presume cv-schema.xsd"
>

  <header
    name="Branden Vennes"
    email="b.n.vennes@gmail.com"
    github="b-vennes"
    site="www.brandenvennes.com"
  >
    <summary>
      API and backend solutions engineer with 6 years of experience.  Develops high-quality and robust service solutions using a variety of tools including SQL databases, NoSQL databases, and event streams.  A strong knowledge of cloud best-practices and a history of deploying dozens of applications to live environments with hundreds of thousands of users.  AWS cloud practitioner certified.  Expertise in Scala, Go, Python, and TypeScript.
    </summary>
  </header>

  <experience
    business="The Walt Disney Company"
    title="Software Engineer II"
  >
    <start-date year="2022" month="6" />
    <end-date year="2025" month="8" />

    <detail>
      Developed production ready microservices supporting internal development teams with easier access to event-driven architectures and tooling including stream replication, snapshot, and lineage tracing services
    </detail>
    <detail>
      Automated the deployment of data ingestion pipelines unifying tedious tasks across GitHub, Jenkins, Databricks, and Slack into a single streamlined workflow
    </detail>
    <detail>
      I developed build pipelins in Jenkins and GitHub Workflows to compile, test, and run verification steps on my team and other teams codebases.  This includes the work I did with generating code.

      Constructed build pipelines with Jenkins and GitHub Workflows to automate the software development lifecycle including compilation, testing, verification, and approval
    </detail>
    <detail>
      I worked with Kubernetes, Datadog, and AWS CloudWatch to monitor and ensure production stability.
    </detail>
  </experience>

  <experience
    business="Topl"
    title="Blockchain Platform Engineer"
  >
    <start-date year="2021" month="3" />
    <end-date year="2022" month="5" />
    <detail>
      I developed a tool to query blockchain transactions using key-field and full-text searches.  The service was deployed with a MongoDB for indexing data and could be accessed using an authenticated Protobuf endpoint with query streaming support.
    </detail>
    <detail>
      I developed an API for managing staking and wallet keys in blockchain nodes.
    </detail>
    <detail>
      I implemented end-to-end API tests using Postman with CI/CD integration using the Newman test runner.  The tests provided coverage over API use-cases and also provided documentation for end users on how to call the API's actions.
    </detail>
  </experience>

  <experience
    business="Viewpoint Construction Software"
    title="Software Engineer I &amp; II"
  >
    <start-date year="2019" month="9" />
    <end-date year="2021" month="4" />
    <detail>
      I implemented new pages, components, and functionality for a cloud web application for managing construction software
    </detail>
  </experience>

  <experience
    business="Viewpoint Construction Software"
    title="QA Automation Engineer"
  >
    <start-date year="2018" month="8" />
    <end-date year="2019" month="8" />
    <detail>
      <!-- TODO -->
    </detail>
  </experience>

  <education
    school="University of Portland"
    degree="Bachelors of Science"
  >
    <start-date year="2015" month="8" />
    <end-date year="2019" month="5" />
    <detail>Computer Science Major</detail>
    <detail>Mathematics Minor</detail>
  </education>

  <certification name="AWS Cloud Practitioner" />

  <skills group="TODO">
    <skill><!-- TODO --></skill>
  </skills>

</resume-content>
